<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AHMED AL-TAKROURI</title>
    <link>https://ahmed-altakrouri.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on AHMED AL-TAKROURI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ahmed-altakrouri.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Clustering Linkedin Profiles</title>
      <link>https://ahmed-altakrouri.github.io/posts/clustering-linkedin-profiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahmed-altakrouri.github.io/posts/clustering-linkedin-profiles/</guid>
      <description>Overview: This notebook presents my efforts to construct a simple model with intensive feature extraction, primarily based on Sentence Transformers BERT. Despite its simplicity, resting on K-means, there is significant room for model refinement and complexity enhancement.In essence, the algorithm presented below forms an excellent foundational or baseline model for addressing the problem of clustering LinkedIn profiles into similar groups.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief rundown of the algorithm:
Extract BERT embeddings for sentences or textual data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraud Detection from ML to Actionable Insights</title>
      <link>https://ahmed-altakrouri.github.io/posts/fraud-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahmed-altakrouri.github.io/posts/fraud-detection/</guid>
      <description>Overview: In my method for detecting credit card fraud, I perceive it as a two-category classification problem. Yet, due to the significant disparity in the distribution of data, constructing a suitable decision boundary becomes a complicated task in credit card fraud detection. To navigate this issue, I adopt a systematic procedure.My first step involves examining the distribution of data variables related to fraudulent and legitimate transactions to enrich my comprehension of the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net Profit Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://ahmed-altakrouri.github.io/posts/net-profit-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahmed-altakrouri.github.io/posts/net-profit-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>Overview: This notebook aimed is to demonstrate the solution for simple regression problem, predict net profit given a set of attributes, first I start with simple EDA understand the data numerical and categorical distributions. Then I fit simple statistical model followed by linear regression and more complex one. each model includes scoring metrics and explanations. Finally, I communicate final finding of prediction of the provided Out-of-sample test set and the including factors or attributes that decided the final predictions using shapley values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ahmed-altakrouri.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahmed-altakrouri.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>As a seasoned data scientist with over 6 years of professional experience, I have a proven track record of leveraging the power of machine learning and AI to drive business success. My expertise ranges from natural language processing to complex forecasting models, and I am constantly seeking out new and innovative ways to solve difficult problems. My main areas of interest include Probabilistic Machine Learning, Causal Inference, Natural Language Understanding, and Bayesian Inference, and I have achieved substantial results in these areas, as evidenced by my various successful projects and publications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
